Podcasting 2.0 for January 23rd,
2026, episode 248. Thingamajigger!
Welcome from a very cold, cold America.
It is time for Podcasting 2.0.
This is it.
This is where we talk about podcasting.
It says it right there on the label.
This is the board meeting
of Podcasting 2.0.
In fact, we are the only boardroom
that doesn't host a party at Davos.
I'm Adam Curry here in the Texas
Hill Country and in Alabama.
The man who codes with Claude
and conquers with confidence.
Say hello to my friend on the other
end, the one, the only, Mr. Dave Jones!
I've had Robbie Dupree in my head for,
like, days now. It will not go away.
Robbie Dupree? Which song?
Steal away, dun-dun-dun-dun-dun.
Why don't we steal away?
Really? That's a, that's a, that's a,
that's in hot rotation on Yacht Rock.
Oh, is that a, is that a Yacht Rock song?
Oh, yeah.
Oh, that's a total Yacht Rock song.
Absolutely.
You ever listen to Yacht Rock on,
like, do you have a Sirius XM?
No, I don't have Sirius XM.
Oh, yeah. Sirius XM has
a Yacht Rock channel.
Did Robbie Dupree have any
other songs that were hits?
No, of course not.
Or is that it?
No, no, that was it.
No, it's like, it's Robbie Dupree, it's
Rupert Holmes with the Pina Colada song.
These are all, these are
all Yacht Rock classics.
Yeah, it's beautiful.
Eddie Money has to be on there somewhere.
On tonight.
Sorry. Sorry. Sorry.
Two tickets to paradise.
I've got two tickets.
Hold on a second.
Let's see.
Let's see what other, let's just,
let's just go to the YouTubes.
Let's see.
What comes up as Yacht Rock playlist?
Is REO Speedwagon, is that Yacht Rock?
Keep on loving you?
Yeah, I'd, I would say, what is this?
Uh, what do we have here?
Ooh, how come I'm not hearing anything?
Oh, here we go.
Remember Key Largo?
Yeah.
Oh, yeah.
Bertie Higgins?
That's good.
The Yacht Rock is almost
all one-hit wonders.
Oh, yeah.
Well, here's a, here's a whole playlist.
Let me see.
Oh, yeah.
This Kenny Loggins?
Absolutely.
Yacht Rock all the way.
Oh, yeah.
Number two on the list.
Yeah.
Number two on the list
is, uh, there it is.
There's your.
I cannot get it out of my head.
And right into.
Yeah, baby.
What a fool believes.
Oh, yeah.
And then the classic.
The classic.
Remember this one?
Boss Gags?
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Come on.
You, you know it.
Oh, oh, oh, uh, is this
their, uh, Hall and Oates?
No, no, no, no, no.
Here's his voice.
Where it's rocking it here
for you on Yacht Rock.
This is Player.
Their hit.
Baby.
I'm back.
Oh, yeah.
This is, oh, oh, and then, of
course, we have the classic.
Seals and Crofts.
That's right.
And then we have, uh, oh, yeah.
Yes, classic.
Come in Jamaica, winner.
Oh, yeah.
Remember on and on?
One more, one more.
On and on.
This is also classic
Yacht Rock, everybody.
Looking glass.
Who, who could forget them?
There has to be Little River
Band on there somewhere.
Oh, no doubt.
No doubt.
Wow.
I have not listened to
these in a long time.
I've been, I've been stuck
in the Christian hits, man.
Little River Band.
Yes.
Nails it.
Reminiscing is the other one.
Oh, reminiscing has got to be on there.
Hurry, don't be late.
I can hardly wait.
I said to myself.
Wait, wait, wait.
Wait.
But a classic from Dr.
Hook and his medicine show.
Come on, baby.
Drink.
Remember Dr.
Hook and he had that, he had that
eye patch on with a cowboy hat.
The problem with all, the problem with Dr.
Hook era of music is that
it was all on eight track.
Oh, well, of course.
And those things vanished.
Like, I mean, like nobody
had, people have vinyl, but,
but eight tracks didn't survive.
Like they, they just, like they,
they melted from time or something.
Yeah.
It's just, you know, that you can
still find them in, uh, in like,
you know, some classic car.
Like I looked at a, an
El Camino the other day.
Why did you look at an El Camino?
Oh, I really have wanted an
El Camino for a long time.
No.
Yeah.
It's an SS.
Beautiful.
Oh yeah.
That's got the, they could
get those with a 454.
That's what it's packing, baby.
The only problem is it is,
um, General Lee Orange.
Ooh.
Yeah.
Like, I don't know.
It's one thing to buy a classic.
That's a bold statement.
Yeah.
It's like, then I have to repaint it.
And I'm like, I don't think so.
Hmm.
Yeah.
But it had an eight track.
Orange is a little much.
It had an eight track in it.
Eight track player, at least.
I think that I, I should have
looked and seen what was in there.
Eight track sucks so bad.
I mean, you had to like, you had to switch
and listen to a different song to rewind.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
Just switch tracks.
And you hear, you hear the heads go.
Yeah.
Everybody.
We're talking about podcasting now.
Yeah, that's right.
Yes, we are.
Podcasting all over the place.
Bitcoin orange, yeah.
Bitcoin orange.
Uh, Hey, uh, congratulations to Sam Sethi.
Uh, and, uh, and the
kids over there at, uh,
true fans close their round of
funding was the big news today.
Oh, nice.
Okay.
Power.
Yeah.
I haven't, I haven't heard power yet.
So yeah, it was interesting.
He was talking about, um,
I was talking to some other hosting folks
earlier this week about, uh, bot traffic.
And so the way, if I
understand it correctly,
the way true fans hosting will work is
they will allow you to turn off bots.
Now, if you turn off the
bots, that means that Apple,
which appears to be one of
the biggest bots these days,
because it's sucking
everybody down for, uh,
for transcripts and chapters and whatever
else question is what will happen if you,
if you block the, uh, the Apple bots,
which truly are using
quite a lot of bandwidth.
So I've got this, uh,
I've got an interesting idea that I want
to throw out to the boardroom here.
All right. Boardroom. Hello.
Pay attention, everybody.
But I, I don't want to, I don't
want to hog up the, the mic though.
So if you, if you got, we can talk about
it later, but I think it's related.
I mean, I think we both have
some vibe coding to talk about.
So we can do that now or you can be, why
don't you talk about your vibe code?
Dude.
What's up, dude?
Dude, I'm almost there.
I have been, I have been wanting to
get off of windows for my podcasting
ventures for years and
years, years and years.
And, uh, so because, uh,
our mutual friend, Paul had
recommended to me to take a look at
Omarchi, which is March Linux with,
you know, with the tiling window manager.
Oh, as they say, opinionated Linux.
It's Linux with even more
David Hanemeyer Hanson is what
it is. Who's that? I
don't know who that is.
DHH, the guy, the inventor
of Ruby on Rails.
Oh, oh, okay.
He's the guy that like he started, he
didn't, he's the mind behind Omarchi.
Oh, hold on. We're not lit.
I'm sorry. My mistake.
Oh, uh-oh.
Thank you, board meeting.
Thank you, boardroom, for
reminding me of that.
Uh, yeah, this stuff
needs to be automatic.
So I, so I loaded it up on, uh, you
know, I think I just need a test box.
I still have that Surface Pro 6.
Oh, yeah. Uh-huh. The one that was
giving you trouble for a while?
Well, it wasn't giving me trouble. Uh, oh,
no, that was an older one. No, that was,
that was a different machine.
This one was running as my,
um, what do you call it?
Uh, what's the, uh, what's
the open, uh, you know,
the one that had like
what you use for the,
for your Bitcoin, uh, node
for your Albi. What is it?
Oh, Umbral?
Umbral, yeah.
I was using it for an Umbral.
Uh, but whatever reason that just kept,
you know, I had to upgrade to the
new, it just, it became a mess.
The Umbral over time just,
I felt, I got my Umbral fixed, by
the way. Oh, you did? I'm good.
It's, it's working.
Yeah.
So I've been, and ever
since I got the start nine,
that box is so rock solid.
It's just, it's just running.
I don't, I haven't looked.
I mean, I pull up my Albi, my, uh, uh, uh,
I'm forgetting all kinds of low
T ladies and gentlemen, uh, my
helipad, you know, that kind of stuff.
It's, it's all on that box.
Works great.
Love it.
Don't have to think about it.
Um, but so I decided I'll install Omarchi
on this because if you can install on
this, which are notoriously messy hardware
systems, I think the Surface Pro 6,
just Surface in general, which
I believe is now discontinued.
Completely unreliable hardware. Yeah.
Unreliable. Well, installed great. And,
uh, really?
Oh yeah.
Right out of the box.
Nope.
Well, no, that's not true.
I had to do one thing
for the wifi, which of
course is very typical.
Um, but it was interesting because
I've been using Gemini now.
I've dropped Grok.
Grok has dropped.
I started, I started using
Gemini mainly because I
got a free, you know, pro
account with my phone.
And I think that's the same
thing that happened to Alex.
He started using it because
he got a free plan,
like some free time on it for a few, it's
like three months or something like that.
Yeah.
But I mean, I'm, I'm all
in because for research
purposes, it's dynamite and
I'm all, I'm in pro mode.
So nothing is fast that,
you know, a question
or research topic can take easily a
minute or a couple minutes to come back.
Uh, but because it
has access to Google search APIs and
YouTube transcripts and all this stuff,
it really has, it does great for
research and it gives me the sources
so I can check where it's coming from.
Um, there's some bias in there, but you
know, but it's, it's been very useful to me.
So, uh, so, uh, I, I jump into Gemini
and I say, okay, here's what's going on.
And right away, it's super helpful.
Oh, this is not a problem.
And it says, and by the way, you
know, while we're doing this,
just grab the USB cable,
plug in your galaxy 7z flip.
Cause it knows I have that, of course,
the end that'll tether no problem.
And it did.
And so I got the wifi fixed.
I got the touch screen.
Everything's working.
And I did that at the kitchen
table in maybe an hour, you know,
and most of that time was just
the install taking place.
And I'm like, okay, I am.
And I say,
listen, uh, Gemini, I am ready to, uh,
move my podcasting setup to, uh, and,
and I, I prayed, played for
a day or two with a March.
I like the tiling window system.
That is the way my brain works.
I've like, I thought you would like that.
Yeah.
Oh, I really do.
Being, you know, and all keyboards.
I'm a keyboard guy.
I love keeping my hands on
the keyboard, moving windows
around, you know, different spins,
especially cause it's a limited screen size.
It's just, I'm, I'm blown away.
You know, the, the super key, uh,
space bar brings up the apps you want,
type it in launches.
I mean, it just, it's, it's, it's kind
of the way I've always wanted to work.
Really nice.
Sam, I'm ready to move off.
It's like, um, let's, uh,
let's start with something
that has been impossible in my life.
I want to take my road caster pro to,
and I want to be able to
see all these devices.
Wow.
Pipewire and Helvam did the trick.
Really?
Yes.
And finally, yes.
And, and, and, and so Helvam is really the,
you know, that's really the magic saw.
Pipewire, by the way, is great.
I mean, I've, I've been, the last
time I looked at this, it was,
you know, Jack, what was it?
Uh, also, also Jack, Jack,
Jack, Jack system, you know,
wonky breaks down, falls apart.
Pipewire.
Amazing.
And of course, the only thing that's
really different between windows
when it comes to USB drivers and Linux
is that you can plug in this, uh,
you know, 16 channel USB
device, which is basically what, what
one, one of the devices, you know,
cause you have two different
devices in the, um, in the road caster.
One is the standard secondary
outed recognize that.
No, probably plug the other one in.
It was like, it just shows you one.
It doesn't show you the,
the chat, um, like the mix minus device.
So with Helvam, you can
permanently map those two channels
to, for the system to
recognize it as a device.
And so now I can just pull
up one of three devices
exactly the way I'd want it on windows.
I'm like, Oh, okay.
I've been waiting for this all my life.
And, and Gemini walked me through it.
Then I'm like, you know,
okay, what am I missing?
That's on
windows that I don't have in this environment,
because in order to do my podcast,
I have been working for years and years
with M air list and M air list is a,
is a commercial product licensed product,
but which is really for radio stations.
But with it, I've been able
to build this, this interface
that I like when in essence, I have, uh,
eight, uh, players at the top of my screen.
And when you can drag and drop a file
into it, which I can do pretty quickly.
And, uh, you know, it's
mapped to a MIDI controller.
I have the nano control two from Korg.
So I can control volume, start and
stop, and I can dump the clip out.
Those are basically the, the,
the three things I do with it.
And then I can zoom
in on the waveform if I want to go back
and I can, you know, just by knowing,
just by watching it when
it plays, okay, we're going
to go back five seconds,
click here and I'll start there.
That's what we do with
no agenda all the time.
So I, I tell Gemini, this is what I want.
Surely you can run that in wine.
I'm not kidding.
I mean, wine is really good these days.
Screw wine, but I want,
if we're going to, if
we're going to, I mean,
the whole point of getting away from windows
is not to run a windows app on wine.
Okay.
You're a nativist.
I want to be, I'm going to go native.
I'm going all, I'm going commando, baby.
I'm fair enough.
I do not want to be running crap in wine.
And by the way, audio
stuff, notoriously iffy
when it comes to wine.
So I just didn't want to go that route.
So I say, you know what,
here's what I want to build.
Within an hour, I replicated
this whole system using,
of course, Python, um, using
the QT, uh, UI framework.
QT, not GTK.
Interesting choice.
No, QT six.
Very, very, very slick.
It draws the waveforms.
It does.
I mean, everything then add to that,
um, Mido for, uh, for the MIDI connection.
I mean, I literally said, okay, I want it.
Now I want to be
able to map these buttons to these
buttons on my, uh, on my MIDI controller.
The code spits out.
I run the code and I can right click
on a button and then it can learn,
learn the MIDI control that I, which is
easier by the way, than
the actual M air list.
It's easier to do it in
the system that I built.
I mean, it's so basically it's using G
streamer as the, as the audio engine.
So I can mix these different, uh,
these different things together.
The long story short is
within a week or two,
I will be switched over.
And, and, and I, I guess I'll
open, cause I made a repo.
Woo.
Look at me.
I'm going to, so I'll, did you, did you
make a repo? Are you going to open source?
Not yet.
Oh yeah.
Of course.
I want everybody to enjoy and
for people to improve upon it.
Um, but I mean, it's, it's, it's even better
than what I had because the way I work,
and maybe not everybody is going to work
this way, but I, you know, so I have,
um, uh, a folder tree, a full, a file
tree open in, um, uh, in this M air list.
So, and I categorize my clips by topic.
And then there's JCD clips and this
kind of the same for any podcast I do.
Um, so now, uh, another thing that,
that was not possible with this other
system is I can just scroll down to a
clip or if I want to use the
mouse, just click once, boom, it,
it occupies the next available player.
And I was using the
everything search engine.
Uh, if you're familiar with that,
everything search app.
Yeah.
It's open source, uh, search app.
It's really good.
You can just say, okay, I only
wanted to, um, index audio files.
And so I've built into this
file viewer, you know,
a quick little shortcut.
You type it in, you get all the, cause
you know, I'm always looking for an
old clip or something or a
jingle or something like that.
And it populates the list, click, boom,
it's loaded super fast.
And so I'm doing all this stuff
and this is within an hour.
I mean, sliders are working, faders
are working, the mix is working.
And, and then all of a
sudden Gemini is like,
Oh, you ready to build the cart wall?
I'm like, Holy crap.
A what?
A cart wall?
Cart wall.
Yeah.
This is where you load up
a whole bunch of stuff.
Like, you know, bombshell, you know,
that you can just, you have the, your
little, Oh, like a, like a soundboard.
Yeah.
It's a cart wall.
It came up with the name cart wall.
And, and so, and so I'm, which is correct.
And I have to say,
I was well impressed at the speed, at
the, uh, at the context window size, um,
the cross chat understanding of,
because at a certain point says, yeah,
this will work great on
your surface pro six,
which was a whole different, um,
a whole different window that
I've been working on that with.
I'm, I'm pretty impressed to be able to,
now I still don't, I mean, I'm basically,
they're paying me extra money
to do it because I don't
see how my free account
or even $20 a month
can any, in any way compensate for the
cycles that have been used making this,
but Holy mackerel, this is
just, it's been exciting.
It really has been.
And this, and so to say AI has
improved my life in this area.
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
I need a screenshot of your new app.
I want to see it.
Okay.
I want to see what you've
built this, this, this, uh,
in their list clone type thingamajigger.
Yeah. In fact, I'm going to call
it the podcast thingamajigger.
What is that?
I want that to be your repo name.
The thingamajigger.
I got to write it down.
The, the podcast thingamajigger
is sounds great.
Well, so my own, um,
own, uh, dive in with,
with, so I, I've made,
I think this is the natural
progression that people go through.
You start with a chat bot, then
you start, then you, you know,
you start in the chat bot world.
Then you go to like in your IDE,
whether it's cursor or Juni and jet
brains or whatever you're like, you know,
whatever this is, copilot,
some sort of add on that's living
in your IDE programmer, uh,
programmer tool with you.
Then you, then at some point you
jump to the, just the command line.
You just have an independent agent.
That's just going to, this lives in the
command prompt on the system, because that
way it just has full access to everything.
You know, it just understands how
to do everything on the system.
And so I made, I made that
plunge with clawed code.
And, um, so, uh, the first,
the first thing I had to do, there's
this thing, uh, at my day job and I'll,
I'll, I'll describe this.
There's an app that it's a production,
uh, there's two, there's two apps.
And this is, this is going
to be, this is going to be interesting
for, uh, for a number of reasons.
So there's two basically identical apps.
They communicate with an in-house custom,
uh, system, uh, platform that we wrote.
And it, all it does is takes
a file and uploads it with a,
communicates with an API and
uploads this file to the API.
So, but it does, there's for, for reasons
that are largely unimportant, there's,
there's two different
routes this thing can take.
So there has to be two
separate apps in book.
Trust me, there has to be two.
So there's two separate apps
that are virtually identical,
except for a few different,
like maybe there's maybe a hundred
lines of code that are insignificant.
They're different between these two apps.
What's always bothered me
that these, these apps were
written, uh, maybe seven years ago.
They're .NET C-sharp apps.
They run in windows.
I wrote them in Visual
Studio 2019, I think.
Yeah, a long time ago.
Uh-huh.
So I wrote them in Visual Studio 2019
and, uh, the, the way they're monolithic.
So they have the, the user
interface for the app
is basically just some configuration
box, uh, text boxes and, uh,
and a log window to just,
just so we can keep track of everything.
But these things are monolithic.
So they have to just stay
running on an open desktop all the time.
So you, you have, uh, so
what I've wanted to do,
I wrote them that way and I
just wasn't thinking about it.
I just needed to get this thing done.
You didn't realize you had to dedicate
a machine to it full time, basically.
Yeah.
And it has to stay open on
a desktop all the time.
So really, really the only thing
that, um, and this is running
some fortune 500s accounting.
Is that what you're telling me?
Yeah, maybe.
Uh, but the, so what I've been needing to
do for gosh, for years now, what I've been
needing to do is spend the time to split
this one, this app into two parts.
Yeah. A backend that
just runs and then a UI.
Exactly.
A windows service and a UI
that'll talk to the service.
And it's just like, it's not,
that's not a hard thing to do,
but it's going to take me
10 hours to go through,
create the new repos, copy, paste
over the code, do the testing,
then create an IPC between the two.
What's an IPC?
Uh, interprocess communication channel.
So like a, a named pipe or a,
you know, something like that,
where these, where the front
end can talk to the back end.
Just use XML RPC, man. It's the future.
Soap. Soap. Soap. Soap. Yeah. But, uh,
so inside, inside joke, everybody.
Yes.
Right.
Yeah.
Uh, the, so this is my, like, who can peel
off 10 hours to recreate a thing that
already is working, you
know, and you, and it's,
you're not going to get anything for this.
All you're going to get is once every
few months when this thing crashes for,
for some reason, you
have to go restart it.
And like, that's the only thing this is.
So as usual, I can't just
commit half a week to doing this.
So I was like, okay, perfect,
perfect trial run for Claude code.
So I grab a copy of the repo, stick it
into a directory, you know, by itself.
So we, you know,
we're not working on the live thing and
I'm like, okay, I described to Claude,
uh, this is a C sharp.net
app that is monolithic.
And I want you to split it in two parts.
I want to have, uh, a, a UI that can,
uh, excuse me, a backend windows
service that can, uh, be installable.
And, uh, then a front end
that communicates with the,
with the service to show me
the logs and blah, blah, blah.
I just gave it a simple, maybe like
a three line prompt, 15 minutes.
It was done.
I installed, I copied it to
the server, launched it
and it just, it worked.
Never touched a single line of code.
Yep.
And I,
and, and the thing that got me and it also,
it said, uh, okay, I split everything.
I split it into three repos, a service
repo, an IPC repo and a UI repo.
And I also created you a bat to two batch
files, one to install the service.
Did that without even asking?
I never even asked for that.
Yeah.
And then I launched, and then I
opened up the UI and it at, it took,
it's the same UI I had before,
but it stuck a new thing
up there at the top,
showing me the status of the service
and a start and stop button.
So I could restart it myself.
That's great.
I was blown away by this thing,
but here's the, but here's the kicker.
So this was perfect.
So I'm like, okay, this is great.
I'm just going to do, I'm
going to take the same prompt
and do it on this other
repo, which is basically
an identical code base.
I'm going to do it on this other repo
and just change the name and say,
do it to this other repo.
I did it completely different outcome.
Oh.
And this time it, it did
not split it into three repos.
It split it into two.
They, they were, they
were differently named.
It did not create the
install service batch files.
I tried to, so I created
the install service batch,
batch file by hand, try, uh,
installed it and installed even,
it gave me a failure, but it still
installed and started.
And then I tried to, and
then I tried to run the UI.
It would never connect to the backend.
It was pretty much broken.
This is the frustration.
This is exactly the frustration
that I've had with it.
And was it in the same context window?
Or did you open up a new window
for the, a new, a new context, a
new chat or whatever you call it?
I know how that works with Claude.
Yeah.
New session.
This is the frustration.
The consistency is nowhere to be found.
I don't understand if it, because
I'm telling you these code bases
are virtually identical.
And I don't know if there's some
sort of temperature that's involved
because there shouldn't be temperature.
I believe is exactly the issue,
you know, because it shouldn't
be temperature on that, the temperature
on that sort of prompt should be zero.
I believe it's the actual
temperature in the server farm.
I believe that actually.
Yeah.
I really think so.
I really think that makes a difference.
You know, the cooling was,
it was half a degree off.
You get different results and
that, and how frustrating is it?
And you can sit there and you
can tell it a hundred times
it will not create what you
had in the previous session.
So the way I got around it is, as I said,
so Claude does this very helpful thing.
I'm not sure if Jim and
I does this or not.
One thing Claude
has that's very helpful is when it creates
a, it'll go into what it calls plan mode.
Yes.
Yeah.
The, the boardroom is
talking about plan mode.
Okay.
So plan, plan mode, it like,
it'll take your prompt.
You can go back and forth manually,
but it'll, a lot of times it'll,
it'll understand it's, it needs to go
into plan mode automatically.
So it'll go into plan mode and it
will essentially write a plan of what
it's going to do.
And it will stick to its own plan.
It will.
Yes.
And so the, the thing about this
scenario is that Claude leaves
those plan files behind.
So what I did was I said, okay, I started
over and I said, look, I said,
I added an extra little bit of
prompt at the end and said, I've
already done this
conversion on another repo.
Here's the plan file from
that previous conversion.
I want you to follow the same exact
plan file as closely as possible.
Does it leave the plan files in the repo?
Is that where it leaves it?
It leaves them in the Claude direct,
like in its working director.
Okay.
Outside of its, out of
the side of the repo.
And this time it did it and
it did it exactly right.
Wow.
Perfectly.
It, I feel like it's all, so the sense
I get from this is that it's sort
of like the experience you have when
you're doing the image generation stuff,
where when you, you,
you get a prompt and it gives you something
really good, it's like, it's improved.
You want to save the prompt.
Yeah.
Change this and do add this.
No, no, we can't.
No, it doesn't work.
It doesn't work.
You, you really, if you ever get
a good result from a prompt,
you need to hang onto that
prompt and keep it forever.
Yeah.
Um, so that was my like first out
of the gate experience with Claude,
but I w which I would say
was highly successful.
I mean, it saved me so many
hours of work on a thing.
Now was it additive?
Not really.
Well, it gave you the service
start and stop button.
It, no, it did.
It did.
Yeah.
No, you're right.
You're right.
And now, well, like in your case,
you were already on windows.
You've, you've mostly replicated
what you had before the, the, the,
the agent helped you do a
sideways move essentially.
Well, no, no, it has
actually improved because
all of the interface
issues that I had, um,
with, uh, M air list, which I would have
loved to be, have it worked differently.
I just said, okay,
implement this this way.
So for instance, um, in M air list, if
you want to, um, do, so if you want
to do a pre-fader listen, so you
want to listen to something, uh,
for instance, end of show ISO.
So if I want to hear an end of
show ISO and I want to, you know,
and so I'll get it from the ISO bot
while you're talking, I'm
listening to you in one ear.
I'm listening.
I'm pre pre-fader listening to
this ISO that I'm trying to get.
And I said an, an in point
and an out point, you know,
cause they don't have time to
like actually edit the file.
So that's a whole different
window that pops up.
There's a whole different, uh, subsystem
of M air list that I'm working in.
It also prohibits
me from doing some other things
with the live, uh, play out system.
So now it just, it's baked into it.
So when I, when I go to pre-fader mode,
it just turns that one player
into a different color.
So I know that it's in PFL mode and then
I can click in the timeline, sit my,
set my in and out points and I'm done.
There's no extra windows
popping up, none of this stuff.
And I can also,
I've also made it so I can select which
interface I want the PFL to go to.
So all, and all these
little improvements, and then also the,
the clip search system that I did,
that was two different applications.
So I've baked that into one now.
So it's definitely,
definitely additive for me.
I think, I think, I think, uh, Leo Laporte
is right in his characterization of,
of this stuff as what the, the, the real
thing that is happening right now is a,
is an unlocking of the ability
to have hyper personalized software.
Yes.
And it is enabling individuals
like myself who have a,
a concept of systems.
So I, I, I understand Linux.
I understand command line.
I understand bash.
I understand some, some Python.
I understand that, you know, I
understand the, the basics of
the computer, you know?
So the, the, the networking, the audio,
I understand all these poor principles
and I've had interactions with them,
albeit very poor interactions
throughout my life, usually
with destructive results, um, to be able
to be able to prompt the right things.
So if, if someone
just sits down and said, okay, I want
to have a podcast play out system,
I doubt it would come up
with anything like this.
It doesn't really exist.
Even the way I customize M
airless is not the way anyone
else has customized it.
So we may see very small companies that
provide software products or services
that they can spin up really quickly.
So I mean, like us, like Godcaster
in a way, I mean, I've created
two or three products that would not be
here because we only really have one,
one and a half, you know,
one developer on the back end, that's you.
And so I've been able to spin
up these, these different
products and optimize them over time
just by knowing what the customer wants,
knowing what I want to build
for the customer and having enough
understanding of the systems to be able to coax
the, the AI into coding what I want.
And the, the actual coding part is
just, it's like a layer on top of it.
Yeah.
I think like, I'm a, I'm afraid to let it
touch code, existing code bases that I'm
already that, that, that are important.
Like I, I've not used any AI on,
on the podcast index API back end.
I'm talking about the API
server itself, you know, I'm a,
I have not let it touch anything in that.
I haven't let it touch
anything in Godcaster.
There's, there's code bases.
I can, I'm really afraid to let it.
Oh, sure.
Sure.
And that's understandable.
I'm just freewheeling my
ass off here, brother.
I'm like, sell it.
People will buy this.
Yeah.
I mean, like the, the, the, uh, but
and it's like, I, I think I'll
get there one day when I,
when I sort of figure
out, okay, I can bring
it in to help me do this particular.
Well, okay.
For instance, the other
day I needed, um, this was
for, uh, something I
was doing in Godcaster.
I, I needed a PHP function that
would just take any string
as input and just return
nothing but an, uh,
and strip out any characters
that were not alphanumeric.
Super simple.
I've written this
function a hundred times.
It's not hard.
It's like one line of code.
Um, if you, you know, if you do it right.
And so I was like, well,
but like, it was faster for me to just
ask Junie to write the function it did.
It was like, boom, done.
And I copy and pasted it in.
Like I can see it, like it's
kind of putting out less fires.
It was easy.
It was quicker for me to have the thing
ride it than to go hunt down another repo,
copy and paste the thing
I wrote out of it.
Yep.
That was faster.
So I think the, the other,
the other thing that I
observed with Claude in this,
I'm going to take this back to
Silicon Valley, just grossness.
Um, this is just the Silicon Valley.
I'm anthropic.
I think, are they Silicon
Valley or are they?
Oh yeah.
Okay.
This, this is their way.
So I'm, I did the $20 a month plan.
They got your money.
We got one.
And it would, so the,
that first repo that I
asked to do the conversion
on that windows app,
it used up like 80 something
percent of my, of my usage window.
Oh, you're, you're, oh, okay.
Not of your credits of your usage window.
So the way this,
the way this thing works is you have,
you have time slices where you can,
you have an overall credit
amount that lasts for like a week.
And then you have, excuse me, you
have a credit amount for the month.
Then you also have individual time slices.
There's one that's a week long.
And then there's one
that's like hours long.
And if you, if you bump up to your
usage window, uh, usage limit for that
window, it'll come back
and say, you know, Hey,
you've used almost everything
for, uh, for this session.
You're going to have to
wait until one o'clock.
Right.
For things to reset.
And so the, the, the, the effect
this has, they give you two options.
Now here's your options in the,
prompt in the, in the, in the app is
you can either stop and wait for your,
for your time window to
reset or upgrade or upgrade.
Exactly.
Or you can upgrade.
And the next plan is $200.
It goes from 20 to 200.
But see, this is what I've been saying.
And I, I don't think that's
a Silicon Valley ickiness.
It's, they've been giving this away.
They've not, they've been
losing 90% on, uh, you know,
on, um, their, their cashflow
because it, you know,
for every dollar you spend, they're giving
you $10 worth of compute.
So they have, they, and 11 labs has
figured this out because we use 11 labs
for our, uh, for our, the,
we call it your town live.
So, um, you can do a couple
of different things.
You can load up to the podcast.
You can have the, uh, most
recent episode from a,
from a podcast play in you,
in this live 24 hour stream.
Yeah.
It does music.
It does, uh, station IDs, promos.
Now, most churches don't have somebody to
voice promos or do a local news report.
So I built a little quote unquote
studio and, um, you know,
and so you just copy, paste some
texts in there and it, and
it's actually pretty good.
I mean, the, the voices that I've, that
I've selected for this, they can use it.
Customers can use any voice they
want, but works pretty well.
And so just from running a few different,
uh, uh, servers like yours, Gordon,
uh, hello, Fred, uh, hello,
Franklin is still on it.
Uh, although paying customers
now use their own API
key for 11 labs, you know, it's like all
of a sudden, Oh, it's 140 bucks a month.
All of a sudden, but, but it's fair because
you are using those compute cycles.
Now what I'm personally now
thinking is, well, in two years,
maybe less when all of these Nvidia
cards have to be replaced by the
hottest new Nvidia thing, I want to
go buy a couple and use them at home.
Yes.
That's, that's, that's the ticket.
I was talking to Alex last night
and I made the same point.
I think the future of the, of
all of this stuff is clear.
And this goes back, this is
kind of what I was getting at
with the Silicon Valley ickiness.
The future of all this stuff
is it's going to be local.
You're, you're going like the, everything
is running to hardware right now is going,
is moving from discrete GPUs and then
a system on a chip, uh, excuse me,
a system on a chip with a
discrete GPU connected by PCIe.
It's moving to unified memory with an,
with an APU or NPU built on the package.
Like Apple stuff.
You mean?
Yes, exactly.
It's going to, so the right,
the new Ryzen hardware is
that way, uh, the Nvidia
hardware, like in the DGX spark.
And that it's also that way.
And you'll, the future of hardware
in general is going to be, you know,
128 gigs of Ram on an SOC.
And it's just unified memory that's
shared by the GPU and the, and the CPU.
And when we get to that point, like,
so one thing, one thing I've been doing
is I've been testing a whole bunch.
We have for a project at
work, uh, my day job, we
have, I've set up a, uh,
a llama server and we're
testing some, uh, some
different models for some things.
And so the, uh, the model that I've
been testing with right now is
GL, GLM 4.7 flash.
That model is fantastic.
It is amazing at generating code.
Like if, if you,
if you had 128 gig of RAM, unified memory,
local machine running that GLM 4.7 model,
oh, you could cook man
with, with open code,
which is like an open source
version of cloud code.
It supports plugins just
like cloud code does.
You, I think within two,
two to three years,
local LLMs that rival
what Claude and them are
doing are going to be
completely accessible.
And isn't this, we were actually talking
about this last night in our group chat,
isn't this where, I mean, the whole
world has always centralized,
decentralized, centralized, decentralized,
with this most recent 365 outage where
the whole corporate world had no email?
Yeah.
I mean, come on.
It's like, it's like a no brainer.
We've, the whole internet was built for
decentralized use and everyone's like,
oh, the cloud, put it in the cloud, put
it in the cloud, cloud, cloud, cloud,
cloud, because they didn't want to pay
Dave Jones to maintain the servers.
Oh, I mean, oh, so much smarter.
Look, I got the, I got
the pitch from Amazon.
But then when it goes out, like
the whole world falls apart.
The lie, the lie of the cloud has been,
and it's been the lie, the lie of,
of big tech from the beginning.
Do you remember, do you remember
when the cloud push first started?
Of course.
The big talking point was, as an IT
manager or sysadmin or anything like that,
you heard this ad nauseum until
you were blue in the face.
You heard the phrase from sales guys,
tech sales guys, you can, this will,
moving to the cloud will allow you
to convert from CapEx to OpEx.
Yeah.
Yes.
Except your OpEx is X10.
Yeah, exactly.
But, but that was a lie because
the, you, you converted to OpEx,
which only just means a
month, monthly billing.
You converted to OpEx net.
And then in the last seven to eight years,
all the cloud providers have switched back
to, you have to buy a year in advance.
Yes.
Which is CapEx.
So it's not back to CapEx again.
Yes.
They're liars.
They're liars that we saw this with,
with Intuit and QuickBooks Online.
They were giving that
away, that product away.
Giving it away.
I mean, you could get that thing in the
early days when they first launched it.
You could get that thing for nothing.
Like 50 bucks a month.
It came free, it came free with your,
with your tax, with your TurboTax.
Yeah.
Buy a Pixel and you got a free, you know,
it's like free three months of things.
Yeah.
You could get that thing.
Now it is through the roof expensive.
Yeah.
Through the roof and it goes up on a,
and the price increases on
a predictable schedule.
And you're, you're, now
you're in the treadmill.
So that whole thing and, and the way it
was being sold in the early days is,
you know, hey, switch the cloud version
of, of your accounting software.
It's because it's so much cheaper.
Big tech will lie to you all the time.
And I think that the story of,
I think the story of AI is going to be
that it is going to empower people,
coders, because I don't know that AI is
going to be super useful for much beyond
code, you know, and tech oriented
things, general knowledge stuff.
I mean, it's still just kind of
lame, but like outside of, you know,
that special use case is going to
allow technologists and coders.
And those kinds of people to hyper-personalize
and bring their stuff back out of
these big tech stacks.
Yeah.
I mean, there's stuff like
N8N, you familiar with N8N?
What does that sound familiar?
It's a, it's an AI workflow builder.
Okay.
So, so you can connect a model to,
you know, to a, to a cloud model,
something local to some other
service, you know, it's,
you basically draw a little flow chart.
And of course you can buy their service
so you can get the open source product.
But I just see in general,
across all types of services,
we have to move away from
these gigantic services.
I mean, Cloudflare, it will
be the last one to go.
And that's a complicated one just because
of the nature of, of web traffic and,
you know, just caching.
That's, that's complicated.
But why in the world would you rely, I
mean, this latest 365 outage, I mean,
because we saw some bounces
coming back from Marriott.
Okay.
Marriott.
Oh, it was everybody.
Yeah.
It was everybody.
I mean, this is when I, you know, when
I tell Tina, it's like, Bob, like the,
the, the 365 took out corporate emails.
Well, like Marriott.
And then she's like,
she realized, oh crap.
Well, that's a problem.
Yeah.
It's a huge problem.
This, this stops business
dead in its tracks.
You know, it's just, it's, it's, I
just don't think it's useful anymore.
And of course, ultimately we
have to eventually, I hope,
go back to allowing people to run
a small service from their house.
You know, this, this will be problematic
because of the asynchronous nature of
cable, internet access, et
cetera, et cetera, et cetera.
And legalities and all this stuff,
but we have to decentralize it eventually
because these big outages will only get
worse and worse and worse.
And life will just come to a
grinding halt every single time.
I mean, I could, you know,
the good thing is like most,
most people have available
to them at their home.
Resources they don't even know exist.
Yeah.
Like a corporate, you could
probably call your, call AT&T.
If you have AT&T fiber or some
kind of cable fiber or whatever,
you can probably call them right now and
get like a quote unquote corporate plan and
get a static IP and all
this kind of stuff.
And you could just start
serving things from your house.
Well, even, even with Tor, because that's
what Start9 uses and Umbral as well.
I am perfectly happy accessing my
Start9 because I run a Nextcloud on it.
It's fine.
You know, I start up or bought or bought
onion thing, whatever that is on my phone.
And it's like, oh, okay,
this is working just fine.
You know, I can give somebody that
address and then they can access it.
You know, it's not like complicated,
uh, nat traversing and all this stuff.
And of course we have other
ways to do that as well.
But for simpletons or noobs or whatever,
plebs, whatever you want to call them,
you know, that type of system that
you can run yourself for your family.
Now, of course, email is
complicated because of
SMTP blockage and there's
all kinds of issues.
But man, I love Void Zero, who has been
running my email server for over a decade.
I mean, it is, I just love the fact
that my email works, you know, and,
and we can stop certain things.
We can hamper things.
We can do all kinds of stuff
to make it customized for me,
for the way I want it to run and what
I want it to allow and not allow.
You know, and, and I don't know, it's
just, it's, it seems like we're,
we just went down this
path and we all went nuts.
And so AI, yeah, I mean,
you're absolutely right.
It's still too expensive, but it'll,
it'll start becoming available
and I'll just put something
here at the house and I'll just use that.
Well, I started, you know,
I tried to make this point a while back
and I don't know if it's true or not,
but it feels true to me that,
that I feel like, you know,
a lot of the expense of the
local AI components right now,
it's not just an accident of
the market being in a bubble.
I think it's also somewhat
intentional because
like RAM is incredibly
expensive right now.
You know, the RAM shortage is nuts.
Yeah, it is bad.
Well, that, who does that help?
Big tech.
Yeah, of course.
Because they're the only
ones that can afford it.
I think it's beyond just a coincidence
that this, that these things are very,
these components are very expensive
for home users to get their hands on.
Because if they weren't, the demand for
big, for the big hyperscaler AI providers,
I think would vanish.
I think that's part of the moat.
Maybe.
Is the, is the, the
bubble induced expense.
Well, I think it's just poor planning.
I don't know.
It seems more like supply
chain, like people just buy,
I don't know if that's on purpose.
It's just the way the beast works.
I think no one was thinking about it.
They, I just, I don't know.
I have a gut, I have a feeling
that the, that part of the whole,
you know, incestuous financial cycle
between the big AI providers is to push,
yeah, is to push the price up where it's
out of reach of anybody that's not them.
I think maybe, maybe,
if you had, if you had,
if you had a DGX spark level
equipment that was 1200 bucks.
Yeah.
Oh, I mean, people would be
buying them like hotcakes,
but because they're
$4,000, most people won't.
Yeah, but it's, but their
whole business, listen,
Silicon Valley's business
model online is advertising.
That's, so they're in a whole new, a
whole new world that, you know, like, oh,
we got to actually
charge people for stuff.
And yeah, people will pay 20
bucks maybe for the chat bot,
you know, but that gets old.
It'll be the first thing to go.
I think the world of software developers
is quite small on a, on a, on a scale.
So they're always going to try and
find things that will, you know, the,
the parlor tricks, you know,
like art generation and song generation
and stupid stuff that, you know,
that will, that it just gets
old where they're, well,
they're still trying to figure out, well,
it's a, it's human level intelligence.
Okay.
Artificial intelligence to me
is like artificial flavoring.
Tastes good.
Yeah.
We'll kill you.
It will kill you at the end.
So anyway, how does this
fit into podcasting?
Yeah.
I don't know that that part does.
Well, other than the fact
that, well, well, uh,
CC Lawton created a
podcast index MCP server.
Yes.
Which, uh, yeah, we, we didn't have a show
last week, so we didn't talk about it.
Have you, uh, fired this up?
No.
And I'm going to put the, um,
put the GitHub issue talking
about it into the boardroom.
Um, I have not had time to fire it up,
but he came back today and
said he wrote a sample app.
Oh, so it's a sample Android app
that uses the, that uses this.
Oh, wow.
Did he email us both about this?
I haven't seen this.
No, he just posted in the issue.
Oh, okay.
In that issue as a reply.
Mm-hmm.
So it would be good to have people
jump in and give this a whirl if,
if anybody has time, uh, to do it.
Uh, it's still on my to-do list, but
how, how does it, my, my question is,
since I'm not
familiar enough with MCP to know what
the backend of the MCP looks like is,
I'm not sure how it
is translating for those who don't know
what MCP is, it's a model context protocol.
It's basically a, it acts
as a proxy between an
AI agent and some API
based service somewhere
that you want to get information from.
So it, it tell, it, it allows the,
if you ask a question to an
agent about podcast index data,
having an MCP interface to the AP,
to the podcast index API would
allow the agent to call and ask for
that API information in a way,
in a reasonable, sane way.
It can, it can intelligently talk to the
API in the way that the API wants it to.
The question I have though,
is that I don't know how those
translations play out in practice.
So if you, are there scenarios where you,
where the agent would just
blast the API with sort of
like trying to grip it, you know,
like, you know what I mean?
Like, could it just flood the API with,
you know, a thousand calls a second?
I don't know.
So that's kind of what I
need to kind of get my
head around is what given a certain set of
inputs from the agent on the front end,
how does that translate into
API calls on the back end?
What, what does that look like?
Speaking about, let's see,
look, uh, C-Law says,
love sending a boost in
the split to podcast index
and get albie.com aired.
Well, the, the, the Albie hub is up.
That's not, that's not mine.
Uh, well, I'm not seeing anything.
In fact, nothing has come in except I,
I just got a 22 stats from the, uh, uh,
from IPFS podcast thing.
No, the, who knows the podcast
index Albie hub is up.
I'm, I'm, I mean, it's up,
it's running right now.
Yeah.
But just cause it's running
doesn't mean it's receiving.
You don't know.
Evidently.
Um, but anyway, that, so that's,
that's an interesting thing that I
think that we, you know, I think
would be a nice thing to put out there
into the world, that MCP server.
Well, I think, you know,
to expand upon that,
because we kind of have
some unique opportunities
with the podcast index, with
an M MPC server like that.
If, if somehow you can
have another service that
can be queried that accesses transcripts
based upon the availability
of a transcript, et cetera,
then you can start to get some pretty
interesting context
searching for discovery.
And I can see some apps wanting to
possibly, uh, experiment with that.
So this brings up, this brings
up the, uh, the idea I had.
That's a perfect segue.
I'm the segue king, baby.
Yeah.
Um, by, by the way, on the GitHub,
on the namespace repo of the GitHub,
I have turned my email
notifications back on.
I turned them off a few
months ago cause I was
just getting flooded with stuff that just
people griping about things.
I just could not, he was
eating up all my mental space.
People just griping about stuff.
Oh no.
So, but, but all that's calmed down.
The, the namespace repo has calmed down.
So I, I've turned email
notifications back on
and I'm going to get back
more engaged with, with that.
So that's what that was about.
The, uh, James had mentioned that it
was kind of a ghost town over there.
And I was like, and I'm
like, yeah, cause it's,
cause I'm not getting any emails from it.
Um, but that's back on.
But, but anyway, the,
the idea I had was, um,
we need a standardized way to attach our
own metadata to a podcast
that does not supply it.
And so the, the reason this came
up for me was that I subscribe,
I think I've mentioned
to you before I'm, uh, I've
subscribed to two shows from twit.
These are, uh, it's windows
weekly and security now.
And a reason I, and I listened
to these shows religiously
because they apply both to my day job.
This is, um, when I listened to these
podcasts, it's work, not pleasure.
When I listened to them, it's work, not
pleasure, but that's a different reason.
It's for a different reason.
Um, and so the problem that I've
had mostly with security now,
not with windows weekly,
but the problem I've had
with security now for
quite a few years now is that there's a,
so the nature of that show
is that Steve Gibson reads,
he reads like entire articles on the show.
And sometimes it's about a topic that
I'd really just do not care about.
It doesn't apply to me.
It doesn't apply to my job.
And I really, really would like
to skip over a chapter chapters.
Well, it doesn't, has
never published chapters
and evidently because
it's podcasting 2.0 and
those guys are racist.
I think even before 2.0 chapters, he was
like, I don't want people skipping ads.
Oh, that's a point.
Yeah.
So, but then what happened was, you know,
I subscribed because I want to
see those two shows supported.
I want them to continue.
So I subscribed to the private feeds.
So those are ad free for a
subscription per month amount.
And I was like, oh, okay, well, maybe they'll
put transcripts and chapters in these.
No.
So the private feeds do not have
transcripts or chapters either.
And I think it's because they're using
Simplecast, which does not support those.
Okay.
So it could be a technical reason, but
it doesn't matter what the reason,
the long and short of it is
that they do not support it.
And so what happened was Apple
released their automated transcripts.
And then recently released,
Apple Podcasts released automated
chapters based on the transcript.
This was awesome for like
three weeks because it
was awesome and also unfortunate
and weird at the same time.
Because what happened was,
even though I'm a paying customer
that subscribes to the ad
free version, suddenly the non-ad free,
the one with ads in it
automatically had chapters.
So I was using Apple
Podcasts for a few weeks to
get chapters in security
now so that I could
flip past all the stuff
that I didn't care about.
And it was so nice.
Wonderful.
So I'm like, well, I guess
even though I'm paying
for it and the private feed doesn't
support the things that I want, at
least I'm getting what I want now.
Yeah, you feel good about yourself.
Yeah.
Well, of course, this was
not going to last because
Apple Podcasts allows you to turn that
off in your Apple Podcasts Connect.
And they clearly got in
there and did that because
suddenly now the chapters are gone.
So...
Because of the ads.
Because of the ads that I don't hear
anyway because I already paid for it.
Yes, for all those seasons.
Yeah.
All those reasons.
So this got me thinking, this has been
annoying me to no end for so long.
It got me to thinking...
I already like where you're
going with this, brother.
I can feel you.
I feel it in my water.
You feel it in your water?
It's a Dutchism.
Okay, okay.
A full of dama water.
Yeah.
So the obvious jumps into everybody's mind
way to solve this, and I don't think it's
the right way, but it is
the one that everybody's
going to think of first
is create a second feed.
Create a second feed that
references the enclosures
of the original feed and put in
your own chapters and transcripts.
You're basically creating a proxy
feed, almost like FeedBurner, right?
Of course, for so many reasons,
it's a bad solution because that feed
is going to get out in the wild.
Now there's going to be another feed
that people are subscribing to.
It's just going to be a mess, and
you don't want to get into that.
A bootleg feed.
Yes, Cotton Jen.
So I just don't want to
do that on principle.
Right.
It seems like, though, instead,
we have an opportunity here to
create a standardized interface that
podcast apps could accept.
So a podcast app could
allow you to put in the
URL of an API that you
run in some sort of way.
It not even has to be an API.
It could be something else.
I don't know yet.
But it could be a podcast thingamajigger.
And the app would simply
call the thingamajigger
whenever it got a new episode and ask the
thingamajigger for amendments,
metadata amendments to that episode.
So let's say Castamatic downloads
an episode of security now.
It takes some universally
identifiable part of that episode,
most likely the episode, the
enclosure URL, and then
passes it to the URL
of the API that I gave to Castamatic and
asks Castamatic for, and asks my API,
is there anything that goes
along with this episode
or anything you want to do?
Like, is there anything I need
to know about this episode?
And that API, of course, will be run by
John Spurlock, as all extra bits are.
Yeah, this is a JS.
JS project.
Yeah, Johnny Player special.
So this keeps everything private.
There's no public bootleg of a
feed that's out there in the wild.
And it's something I'm paying.
So heads up, Daniel J.
Lewis, this is aimed squarely at
you also, because PodChapters.
If I pay, for instance, the way
this could work using Daniel J.
Lewis's podcast chat, PodChapters
service, is I could ask, I could put,
I could have an
account, PodChapters account, and
then get an endpoint specific to me.
Add it into your app.
Add it into my Castamatic.
Mm-hmm.
Then now every time Castamatic
downloads a new episode,
it takes the enclosure
URL and asks PodChapters,
my private PodChapters endpoint, asks it,
is there anything else
you want to add to this?
And it could be just, you
could return just XML.
Mm-hmm.
It could just be extra XML
that comes back in and
gets sort of virtually
merged into the feed
item with, so you're going to get back
from the PodChapters private API endpoint.
You're going to get back a chapters tag and
a transcript tag and all these kinds of
things that you paid for.
I would be paying for these
things to be generated.
App needs to know a standardized way to
communicate with the service in order to
call it and get a response.
So here's the obvious issues.
Great idea.
I am all for, because I had to realign my
heart with people playing my podcast at
2.0 speed, with people
using silent skippers,
because I feel that that's my art and
this is how I want you to consume it.
But of course, I have no say over
how someone wants to consume my art.
They may burn it to a CD.
You know, there's all these
different things you can do.
The minute you introduce a paid service,
because this is no different
than the app, I think,
that James was talking about on
PodNews today, over the past two days,
that skips ads, that reroutes around
tracking URLs, including OP3.
So to have that personally and to use
that personally, completely valid.
The minute this is a paid service, that
paid service has a huge target on its back.
Because the publisher, I
feel, has right to say, hey,
you're taking my content, adding on some
value to it that diminishes my value.
Do you understand what I'm saying?
Because it will, the minute you have this,
one of those extra things in
the API will be skip the ads.
It's just, it's, it's.
Oh, for sure.
Yeah, yeah.
It's clear as day.
So if you have that yourself,
or let's say there's an open source app
that does that, nothing can be done.
And it would be up to the
individual, like you do, like, well,
I'm paying for it over here,
so I feel good about it.
But that will be 1% of the people.
So in theory, it's a great idea,
but I just don't see how anyone can
implement that in a commercial way,
such as an app.
Even if you're taking
donations or, you know,
you have an extra full
paid version, et cetera,
I think that's just asking for trouble.
Yeah, the, I think the concept works.
Yes.
But the, the podcast,
the pod chapters example of a paid
service may be the wrong example.
It could, it would need
to be something like,
it would just need to be something that
I, that you provide on your own privacy.
Yes.
Which, of course, no, which almost
guarantees this won't happen.
Just for you.
No, you will, you will use it.
Just you will use it.
Yeah, this is going to be,
but there's tons of examples out
there of podcasts that just,
for whatever reason, they're just not
giving you something that you want.
And there, it's just an annoyance.
And if you had a way to sort of amend
the feed in a private way, because,
you know, if you know how to do
it, you're going to do it anyway.
Because, I mean, like what, what I
will do, I will absolutely do this.
If, if, if, if Twit does not work out some
way with Simplecast or whoever their,
their private feed provider is,
if they don't work out some way in the near
future to get some kind of chapters or
something into these shows,
I will just write my own podcast
app and just do this all myself.
Yeah, and I think that's, that's what it
comes down to because, and it's just sad.
It's sad that we are in
this, we're in this world,
the podcast industrial complex,
you know, it's like the,
and it's also a mindset, you know,
it's like, oh, I have to have ads.
It's the only way I can make money.
Whereas I'm sure, well, no, it's
proof positive that you pay,
you will gladly pay for Windows Weekly,
you know, you'll gladly pay for it.
But this whole, well, I mean,
Windows Weekly should just add
these things to their ad-free feed.
That's the answer right there.
Well, that's the answer.
That's the answer.
And they can use a commercial service
like PodChapters for that to do it.
And they should.
Or maybe, you know, or maybe
this particular feature
is only available for private feeds.
That would be another way around it.
Like somehow it only, you know, if
you're going to have like some,
something like, you know, something like
Daniel Zay-Lewis' service or whatever,
I don't, I mean, he may want to
not be interested in any of this.
But something like that service could
say, okay, we will provide, you know,
amended XML information based
on your own, like, you know,
your own back-end processing or
whatever you want to add to it.
But it's only going to be for
paid, like, subscription podcasts.
Like, you got to prove that
you're paying for it first.
Yeah.
You know, let's get, so it'd be
like Simplecast or whatever.
I don't know.
I just feel like, I hate, you know,
I hate solving problems for me
in a one-off way and not like,
I always want it to be
like a bigger, open,
public solution to the problem that
other people can do themselves.
It's kind of annoying to
have just some private thing
you've rigged up that
nobody else can enjoy.
Because if, because if
I'm having a problem,
I know that other people
are having the same problem
with other feeds and that kind of thing.
But I don't know.
Maybe, maybe you're right.
Maybe there's no way to do
it in a way that makes.
Leo should just think about his customers.
That's all.
He doesn't care about his customers.
That's the bottom line.
If you're offering an ad-free
feed, add in the bits people want.
Fool.
So maybe, maybe it's not that,
yeah, maybe it won't work.
Just before I, as I remember,
I heard James talking about,
maybe he's going to write up a new
issue or proposal for podcast comments.
Because I guess at PodFest,
everyone discovered that, wow,
people really like the
comments on YouTube.
So we have to have comments on podcasts.
So be on the lookout for
it is what I'm saying.
And we already have comments that work.
Oh, yes.
No, it's just going to be a JSON comment.
Well, okay.
I guess I'll wait and see what he does.
But I think Daniel, Daniel J.
Lewis had a pretty comprehensive
JSON comments proposal already.
Yes.
Yeah.
I think he already wrote back-end
software and everything for it.
I'm just, in general,
just not in agreement that people
desperately want comments on podcasts.
I'm kind of over that.
Chat is fun.
Comments that live forever, not so much.
The YouTube comments, it's part
of the entire video experience.
You know, you're interactive
with the screen.
I find podcasts are just passive.
Comments on YouTube are...
Are typically real-time comments
is really what they are.
Yeah, live.
Yeah.
In live streams, yeah.
Mm-hmm.
And that's cool.
And they suck.
Well, what happens is
on these live streams,
people get in there and they
just treat it like a chat room.
They're talking to themselves.
They're not even really
interacting with...
Yeah.
It's like an ephemeral chat room.
But anyway, I just want
to make sure everyone was
on the lookout for it because it's coming.
But yes, I think there's many, many
comment proposals slash, et cetera,
chat proposals that have been put out.
Well, the other thing that's continuing,
and I'm actively working on this,
is the AI slop and quality control stuff.
And there's a big thread
on the namespace repo.
We really need a better place
for these discussions to happen.
The namespace repo is...
There's all kinds of stuff in there that
has nothing to do with the namespace.
Mm-hmm.
And that's one of the reasons
I turned off the emails
about it is because
there's getting like...
People are talking in there about things
that are like index-related and stuff.
So anyway, it's a big mess.
But the other thread on there is just about
David Marzell brought up podcast quality
control and the AI slop and all
that junk feeds and everything.
So I'm continuing to work on that.
And I've almost got...
I've got everything working.
I just have to put the output side of it
on so where people can pull out the slop.
The marked slop.
Because I've been marking it.
I do about...
I probably do about 10
minutes a day total.
I just have it running
and what I'm really...
I have it running in a window.
I'm like, oh, kanji characters.
Let me check.
That's kind of my main...
Like, oh, kanji characters.
Let me see.
Okay.
Slop, slop, slop, slop.
I'm seeing so much duplication.
So much.
Mm-hmm.
It's amazing how much
is just spam or slop.
It's an amazing amount.
It really, truly is.
I'm just...
It's abusive.
Like, it's so sad people do that.
But I think the general sentiment about...
You know, and you had said
this too, is we should...
You know, we should not be blocking stuff
from being put on the server as of now.
We should not be
necessarily blocking stuff.
There should be some sort of, like, goring
system to help identify these things.
And I agree with that.
For now, it's okay.
It's running fine.
You know, there does...
It does cross a threshold, though, at
some point where it becomes sort of a...
It becomes where you're
having to play self-defense.
Yeah.
Because if we begin to get truly swamped
and overloaded with junk content,
we will have to begin to make...
We'll have to play self-defense to keep
from having it cost us real money.
And the, you know, storage, quote-unquote,
storage is cheap, but not block storage.
Not block storage.
Mm-hmm.
Block storage is...
Disk storage is expensive.
And these are, remember, you got
to remember, these are, these,
these podcasts, these junk
podcasts are going into the database.
Yes.
Yeah, they're not just living...
They're not living on object
storage somewhere for 0.0001 cents.
They're going into a database, and
that is real, you know, that's like a,
you know, that's CPU cycles, that's...
And database storage never goes down.
It just expands.
Yeah.
So...
Well, I mean, the thing...
I mean, really, I've only been marking
two different kinds of things.
It's slop and spam.
And the spam is worse than the slop.
Mm-hmm.
The spam is, is outrageous.
And it would be nice to
find kind of easier ways
to identify it because it's like three
or four clicks, you know,
so you really have to look at the
XML and then you go see, okay,
do you have an enclosure?
And, you know, sometimes
they go through the
effort of putting an
enclosure in that's an
actual audio or video file,
but usually they don't.
And, you know, so it's
just, there's too much...
We could shorten the spam
identification cycle, I guess.
Okay.
And I think, I think the,
the way this will work is when
the feedback loop gets completed
on this next round that I'm finishing
is that it'll, the, the identified,
the human curate, the human identified
problem feeds will feed back into the LLM,
which will generate description
files of what, of what, uh, the signs of
spam feeds and low quality feeds are,
then that will feed back into marking.
It will not automatically
mark it, but it will,
it will feed back into
like a score so that
we can then try, it'll
be easier to identify.
Good.
We'll, we'll work through it.
We'll work through it.
I do like it.
I like it.
I, um, I built it on my, uh,
on my surface so I could
actually use the sound card and,
you know, hitting the P button to play.
That's, it's cool.
That is definitely cool.
The interface is still a little,
it's like, it's kind of slow.
That's slow.
Good for me.
Cycling through with the, with the up and
down arrows kind of lag that bothers me.
There's a little lag.
You're right.
Just a little bit.
Yeah.
I think it's like the, the, the UI updater
loop is a little slow or whatever.
Mm-hmm.
That's it's, it's vibe code, man.
What do you think?
Yeah, baby.
Vibe code and vibe code
in our way to heaven.
Let's thank some people, which
will be real short on my end.
We got, uh, we did get some route tests.
But, uh, now of course this is, uh, I'm
looking at the key send, uh, receiving side.
So it doesn't mean we actually got
these sats or we got 1% of them.
Uh, salty crayon, one,
two, three route test.
The, that was from pod verse.
We got Chad F from fountain
with a hundred sats.
We have, uh, Eric PP.
He used the boost CLI for 33, 33.
Here's some sats.
Salty crayon with three 33 from
podcast guru test boost over key send.
Yes, of course.
Key send works.
Uh, so I, yeah, it does.
Uh, and, uh, and then I hit the delimiter.
So the sats have been pretty low lately.
Although I did see people streaming sats.
Let me see.
Let me just check the streaming sats here.
Yeah.
Uh, Curio caster, Eric PP streaming away.
Uh, it seems to be, it
seems to be the big one.
Yeah.
That's what we got.
Okay.
What do you have on your list?
Well, we got, uh, we got
Buzzsprout a thousand bucks.
Yeah.
Hello.
Shot collar 20 inch blades on the Impala.
Buzzsprout keeping the vibe alive.
Thank you very much.
Boys and girls from Buzzsprout.
Appreciate that.
This is value for value.
This whole project.
We're just sitting here
trying to keep it alive.
Uh, Chuck, Kevin, and Tom a note.
See if they want to be on the show.
It's been like a year.
Oh, it's been a long time.
Yeah.
It's been ages since
we've had the boys on.
I know.
We'll see if they, let's
see if they, uh, come back.
Okay.
Uh, boy, look at here.
RSS.com.
Ben and Alberto.
That 1,001, let's see,
$1,010 and 10 cents.
That's 1,010, 1,010.
Ah, nice.
Bala.
Woo.
Bala, 20 inch blades on the Impala.
The machines keep running
for another month.
Thank you as well.
Dave and Adam.
This is from Ben.
A binary boost corresponding
to the number 42.
Yes.
The answer, as we look forward to 2026
and back at all the years before,
we recognize that the podcast index and
2.0 has been the answer to so many things.
Thank you, team at RSS.com.
Oh, thank you, RSS.com.
Thank you, team.
It's a pleasure to serve you.
Uh, thank you guys.
Uh, we'll see.
We got some boosts.
Uh, let's look back.
I, I got instructions from,
uh, comics for bloggers.
Oh, you have, oh, you have
instruct, you have stuff to do.
He said, do not read last.
He said, he posted on the social
not to read last week's, uh,
not to read last week's,
uh, boost because it could
be interpreted as racist.
So I'm going to skip it.
Oh, I'm looking at it now.
But I, but I did read it.
Yeah, we read it.
Yeah, it's funny.
Okay.
Uh, we got a true, uh, true
fans, anonymous, 4950.
Ooh, thank you very much.
Uh, that was on, that was for episode, uh,
242nd is 247 Aggie five, uh, tone wrecker
through fountain, uh, 2265.
And he said, oh, this is like
a, this is like a haiku.
He says middle of the night underneath
desk rewiring this episode plays.
That is a haiku.
It's a low coup.
Yeah.
More anonymous, 4950 through true fans.
Thank you.
Appreciate that.
And here's the delimiter.
Comic strip blogger.
That was a short list.
Very short.
Comic strip blogger, 17,000 sets.
Uh, let me see.
Let me make sure I'm following all of
comic strip bloggers, uh, instructions.
Yes.
Uh, let's see what he said.
Let me read today's Bitcoin.
Don't, uh, don't read
the one from last week.
Uh, I screwed up the URL
and the Bitcoin gram.
It should be, okay.
I got it.
All right.
So, uh, he says, uh, see 17,000 sets.
He says, howdy fellow AI
users, Adam and Dave.
Today, I want to recommend
company 11 labs.io only
because it was found by two poles born in
Poland also because it has,
apart from text to speech,
incredible AI voice changer that
offers quote full control over the
performance, capture whispers, laughs,
accents, and subtle
emotional cues, unquote.
So podcasting anonymously
is finally possible.
Wait a minute.
CSB AI archwizard.
Hold on a second.
Is this real time?
I don't know.
I don't think it can't be
a real time voice changer.
Interesting.
Full control over the performance.
I don't know.
Well, I'm an 11, 11, 11 labs user and I,
I power you, you're a, I am a power user.
I, I use the API and I think that's power.
Yeah.
I, I think they are very, very good.
Um, they, I think they're
doing good things over there.
It's, it has changed, uh, radio and
it has changed podcasting, but radio,
you know, for
live streams, man, I, I use that all the
time for promos and all kinds of stuff.
You can create music beds.
It's great.
It's, it's, it's very useful.
Very, very useful.
Daniel said CSB should provide a
rules.md file with his booster grams.
I think that's a good idea.
Yes.
Thanks, uh, comics for
blogger, the AI archwizard.
We appreciate it.
Yeah.
Thank you, brother.
Uh, we got some monthlies.
We got Christopher Riemer, $10.
James Sullivan, $10.
Cohen Glotzbach, $5.
Uh, Oestein Barra, $5.
Oh, thank you.
He's coming on right after this.
He is.
Yeah.
They always mutton, meat and music.
Timothy voice, $10.
Gene Liverman.
Hey, Gene.
$5.
Michael Hall, $5 and 50 cents.
Thank you, Michael.
New media productions.
That's Todd and Rob, $30.
Jeremy Gerds, $5.
Derek J. Visker, the best
name in podcasting, $21.
Paul Saltzman, $22 and 22 cents.
Nice.
Always, Paul.
Uh, Damon Kasajak, $15.
Thank you, Damon.
Uh, Silicon Florist, whoever you are, $10.
Chris Cowan, $5 and Terry Keller, $5.
Thank you, guys.
Yeah, thank you all very much.
And I can tell just by the numbers, I hear
some people have upped their numbers.
Thank you very much.
Uh, that probably is
because we were talking
about keeping the podcast
index running and
it can't just be running
on only two hosting
companies because that's pretty
much what it is these days.
Uh, so all these smaller amounts,
they are very much appreciated.
So if you, uh, get any value out
of podcastindex.org, it's API,
the work that is done, a lot of
the work that Dave does, uh,
please consider supporting us.
You can go to podcastindex.org
at the bottom.
There's a big red donate button, support
us there with your fiat fun coupons.
I actually, I think now, uh,
because PayPal, PayPal, they're,
they're going to start expanding.
Those, you'll be able to use other forms
of, uh, digital money to, uh, to send,
uh, to send stuff to us.
And we just appreciate it.
Boosts, of course, are
always appreciated, uh,
through any of the modern podcast apps.
Uh, and let me see, I got travel coming.
I'll be here next week.
Are you here?
We're here next week.
Yes.
I think we're here next week.
That's right.
Okay.
Well, board, boardroom.
Thank you very much for attending.
Stand by for Oystein Berger with
his, uh, mutton, meat and music.
Brother Dave, what you're
doing this weekend besides
keeping warm for the big
storm that we have coming?
Uh, you are going to get it
worse than I am evidently
because it looks like the ice storm
was going to be, it's moved north of us.
So it's, it's north.
Hmm.
Yeah.
It's like, we were like, Birmingham
was supposed to get like, God,
like two inches of ice.
We were like freaking out.
And then now they've said, well,
you're probably not going to get any.
Well, you know about the,
uh, the exploding trees.
Uh, Oh, is that where they, where
they, uh, swell up with water,
with water and blow up?
Extremely cold temperatures tonight.
Please watch out for exploding trees.
Yikes.
Folks, if you hear loud
cracks, stay indoors.
What is that?
Yeah.
I think it's, uh, they just started
some hype about exploding trees.
I guess it can happen
if it gets cold enough.
Sure.
Yeah.
So they already predicted
it would start today and
it hasn't started today
and maybe tomorrow.
So I'm not too, uh, not too
worried, but we'll see.
Austin's not, you're not in
those crosshairs, are you?
You're a little bit set too south.
Yeah.
But Fredericksburg is right on
the cusp of it, but they were,
they were all freaking us out too.
So we'll see how it goes.
So watch out for your trees.
If we survive, we'll be back
next week for the board meeting.
Thank you all for being here for the
one and only podcasting board meeting.
We'll be back next week right
here on podcasting 2.0.
You have been listening to podcasting 2.0.
Visit podcastindex.org
for more information.
Go podcasting!
Take my own tonight.